Understanding Bliss is a drama film directed by William D. MacGillivray.
Elizabeth Sutton, a lecturer from Toronto and Peter Breen,
a professor of cultural studies from St.
John's, Newfoundland, come together in his town for a secret liaison.
All is bliss.
But within twenty-four hours, the affair has collapsed.
A clash of languages, cultures, and values force them to come
to terms with each other's sense of morality.
Elizabeth Sutton, played by Catherine Grant.
Peter Breen/Uncle Henny Penny, played by Bryan Hennessey.
May Breen, played by Rosemary House.
Peter's Father, played by William MacGillivray Sr..
Richard (Turkish Knight), played by Rick Mercer.
Paddy (Beelzebub), played by Paddy Barry.
This is a list of Canadian films which were released in 1990:
The tone is emotional.